# **VALON RAMA**

**FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER** 

VRAMA21@GMAIL.COM

PHILADELPHIA, PA

609.204.3407

) vn

VRAMA21 VRAMA21



VRAMA21.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO

# **TECHNOLOGIES**

# Languages

Python, Javascript

### Frontend

ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Jinja

## **Backend**

Django, Flask, Express, NodeJS, REST API

## **Databases**

MySQL, MongoDB, Postgres, SQLite

#### Other

Git, jQuery, JSON, Microsoft Suite, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

# PROJECTS

## Sheriff Sale

Sheriff Sale is a real-estate data aggregator pertaining tosheriff sale auctions in New Jersey. It scrapes upcoming auction data and fetches associated data pertaining to each listing from external sources such as Trulia and Zillow.

Python, Flask, SQLite, Jinja

## **LetsPlayHockey**

LetsPlayHockey is a resource for hockey players to find, create, and sign-up for local pick-up hockey games. Search players by their skill level, position, and/or their availability.

Javascript, Express, MySQL, React

# Flex Point-of-Sale

Flex Point-of-Sale is a restaurant point-of-sale application. The goal of this application is to bring in newer modern technologies to a category which has been out-of-date and lacked any recent innovations. Flex is built with the idea of complete flexibility. Flexbility to handle any test-case in the restaurant industry, and to handle it flawlessly to increase work productivity and reduce potential errors.

Python, Django, Postgres, React

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 06/2016 - Present | Atlantic City, NJ

### Manager/Supervisor | Marco Polo's Inc.

- Managed a business grossing over \$1 million a year.
- Managed inventory and stock bi-weekly.
- · Recruited, hired, and oversaw training of staff.
- Supervised all floor activity to maintain high standards of customer satisfaction.
- Shifted business strategies resulting in 10%-15% increases in sales and profits each year.
- Integrated, maintained, and upgraded Point-of-Sale software systems, producing higher efficiency and accuracy on delivering products.

#### 09/2013 - 04/2014 | Philadelphia, PA

### Software Quality Assurance Intern National Board of Medical Examiners

- Constructed and executed test cases for web applications based on design specifications and requirements.
- Detected and documented software bugs and potential failure points.
- · Collaborated with developers, business analysts, and project managers to maintain the project timeline and deliverable.
- Ensured applications are fully functional, stable, and bug-free prior to deployment.

# EDUCATION

2019 - 2020

**UPenn LPS Coding Bootcamp** 

Fullstack Web Development

2011 - 2016

Drexel University

Computer Engineering